{"test_questions": [[{"question": "A nicked RNA molecule can be ligated by", "opta": "T4 RNA ligase", "optb": "DNA polymerase", "optc": "T4 DNA ligase", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The tertiary structure of yeast tRNA", "opta": "involves extensive base stacking interactions", "optb": "resembles the 3-dimensional structure of other tRNAs", "optc": "is maintained mostly by non-Watson-Crick base pairing", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of following RNA characteristically contains unusual purines and pyrimidmes?", "opta": "rRNA", "optb": "nRNA", "optc": "mRNA", "optd": "tRNA", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The anticodon is a structure on", "opta": "mRNA.", "optb": "tRNA.", "optc": "aribosome.", "optd": "rRNA.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The genetic material of retroviruses such as HIV is", "opta": "DNA", "optb": "RNA", "optc": "protein", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Retroviruses replicate via __________ intermediate", "opta": "RNA", "optb": "DNA", "optc": "mRNA", "optd": "rDNA", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "During RNA synthesis, the DNA template sequence 5'Tp Ap Gp Cp 3' Would be transcribed to produce which of the following RNA sequence?", "opta": "5'-Ap Tp Cp Gp-3'", "optb": "5'-Gp Cp Up Ap-3'", "optc": "5'-Gp Cp Tp Ap-3'", "optd": "5'-Ap Up Cp Gp-3'", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "RNA instability in alkaline solutions is due to", "opta": "adenine", "optb": "ribose", "optc": "uracil", "optd": "single strand nature", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In RNA, uracil pairs with", "opta": "adenine", "optb": "cytosine", "optc": "thymine", "optd": "guanine", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Two features of the tRNA molecule associated, in converting the triplet codon to an amino acid, are", "opta": "in the T Loop and D stem and loop", "optb": "in the anticodon loop and D stem loop", "optc": "in the anticodon loop and the 3' CCA end", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is the smallest of the RNAs?", "opta": "Messenger RNA", "optb": "Transfer RNAs", "optc": "Ribosomal RNAs", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The mRNA from which of the following would contain a poly-A tail?", "opta": "A restriction endonuclease from E. coli", "optb": "Bacterial alpha-amylase", "optc": "Human insulin", "optd": "Bacteriophage DNA ligase", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the average size (in bp) of a mature t-RNA?", "opta": "80 bp", "optb": "100 bp", "optc": "120 bp", "optd": "140 bp", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What modified base is at the 5' extremity of a capped eukaryotic m-RNA?", "opta": "1-methyl-adenosine", "optb": "2'-O-methyl-guanosine", "optc": "7-methyl-guanosine", "optd": "1-methyl-guanosine", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the function of messenger RNA?", "opta": "It carries amino acids", "optb": "It is a component of the ribosomes", "optc": "It is a direct copy of a gene", "optd": "It is the genetic material of some organisms", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}